ASHISH AGNIHOTRI

+91 94270 36284 • ashishagnihotri2k@gmail.com • linkedin.com/in/ashishagnihotri23 • github.com/Ashish1323

SUMMARY

An **Immediate Joiner**, Software Development Engineer with 2 years of experience in Java, C#, and JavaScript. Excelled in automation, process enhancement, and solution delivery. Led significant projects and catalyzed user growth. Seeking a challenging role to further utilize my skills.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming: Java, JavaScript, C#, React, Selenium, NodeJs, PostgreSQL, Github Bitbucket, NoSQL, Maven, Systemd, Bash, Rest Apis, MongoDB, ExpressJS, JSON

Familiar: Python, CSS, React-Native, HTML5, C++, C

Tool and Tech: Microsoft Azure, Git and Bitbucket, Gitlab, Jira, Postman, AWS, Bootstrap Studio, Docker, IntellIJ, Heroku, Netlify, ChatGPT, MongoDB Atlas, Google, Figma, VS Code, Heroku, MongoDB Atlas

EXPERIENCE

Amazon, Hyderabad: Software Development Engineer (Fixed Contract)

Feb 2023 - Sept 2023

- Spearheaded the development of Amazon's ground-breaking Inhouse RPA Solution, commanding a value of \$1.3 billion in 2019.
- Engineered the automation of Amazon's Coupa Portal, culminating in an impressive saving of 12,500 working hours, equivalent to \$3.16 million.
- Led inaugural RPA dev Bootcamp for Amazon, training approximately 25 developers.

Blueoptima, Bangalore: Software Engineer 1

Jan 2022 - Jan 2023

- Managed the transition of Azure Task Trackers on Integrator (a robust extraction tool), resulting in a remarkable increase in the user base by 5,000 within just one week.
- Revolutionized Integrator's start process from a cronjob to systemd, reducing downtime by 48 percent.
- Transitioned Azure VCS from SDK to Rest APIs, boosting extractions by 65 percent.
- Conceived and implemented business logic for file creation date, addressing a significant gap in Azure's API implementations.

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

Log Analyser

- Participated in a team to develop a user-friendly web app for log data cleaning; presented data in visually appealing table format.
- Supported filtering of data by log types and handling of files up to 2GBs.
- Utilized technologies: Node, ExpressJS, Regex.

We Five

- Led a team to design a question-and-answer platform, similar to sites like Quora; the platform gained 1K+ users
 according to Google Analytics.
- Coordinated team tasks, including quality measurement for major milestones.
- Ensured team compliance to Design Control Procedures according to the project scope.
- Implemented Node, ExpressJs, MongoLab, Bootstrap for web development.

EDUCATION

B.Tech, Computer Science Engineering

2018 - 2022

Dayananda Sagar University, Bangalore, India

Relevant coursework: Data Structures, Algorithms, DBMS, Operating Systems, Object Oriented Programming, Computer Networks, Mobile App Development

EXTRA CURRICULAR

- Contributor to Open Source projects, with over 2 years of experience on GitHub.
- Conducted Web Development Boot-camps at college for 2 years straight.
- · Former Volunteer at MAD, VFCs, and Udaan.